hey guys this looks like a fun one it's
two equilateral triangles with a
distance of two between the Peaks and
through those two peaks it draws a
quarter Circle and it wants to know what
is the area of that quarter Circle if
you want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 so the question is asking us to find
the area of this quarter Circle the area
of a quarter circle is equal to < R 2 /
4 so the only thing we got to do is
figure out what is the radius of this
quarter Circle I'm thinking let's
reflect the whole image down here so now
we have a semicircle and four of these
equilateral triangles in equilateral
triangles all the angles are equal to
60° I'm specifically interested in this
angle right here and we can cut this 60
and half by bringing down this segment
right here and it cut this angle into
30° and now let's focus on this 30
degree angle since the vertex is on the
circle this is called an inscribed angle
and inscribed angles are always half the
inscribed Arc so the measure of this Arc
right here is 60° and if we shift the
angle up here it's now called a central
angle and that is equal to The subtended
Arc so this angle is 60° and both of
these sides of the angle are equal to
the radius now let's focus on this
triangle right here since these two
sides are equal to each other it is an
isoceles triangle and every Isles
triangle the base angles are congruent
so both these angles are equal to each
other since every triangle has 180° this
is only possible if both of those are
60° and now since all three angles are
equal we know this is an equilateral
triangle so that means all the sides
have to be equal so both of these sides
are equal to two so now let's let's
bring back our original figure and let's
focus on the quarter Circle the radius
of this quarter circle is equal to 2 and
now we're ready to use our area formula
in the place of the radius let's plug in
two 2^ 2 is equal to four and these
fours will cancel each other out so the
area is equal to Pi square units and
this is the answer to our question let's
put a box around it the area of this
quarter circle is equal to Pi square
units how exciting